<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Conant | Blog of Webs]]></title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-01T23:51:33.517Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Benjamin Conant]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[conantbenjamin@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Why Development?]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2014/10/23/Why-Development/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2014/10/23/Why-Development/</id>
    <published>2014-10-23T19:01:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-23T19:51:52.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started out thinking that I was going to be an art historian. Somewhere in the middle of my undergraduate years I switched to studying economics (it was more practical), and philosophy (it was more fun). Through the mathematics requirements for economics, I learned that while in middle and high school math had seemed not much more than a boring chore, it was actually just about the best thing ever.</p>
<p>I say ‘just about’ because as my personal mathematical renaissance was in full swing, and my time left in college quickly slipping away, I thought ‘hey, why not try computer science?’ I was immediately hooked. Coding combines the creativity and artfulness of philosophy with the clean logic and involved conceptual manipulation of mathematics. Even better, when you are done working on a coding project you are left not with a paper which you will probably never read again or a bunch of solutions to a set of problems that have already been solved before but a living working computer application that does exactly what you intended it to do. Assuming that your intentions were not frivolous to begin with, this means that your work has created something useful that you and others can use to make life more enjoyable. What could be a more enthralling, challenging, worthwhile, and flat out enjoyable pursuit? </p>
<p>After college I joined Teach For America as a 6th and 7th grade math teacher in a first year charter school located in Newark, New Jersey. The school’s curriculum model was ‘blended learning’ — an instructional philosophy in which students receive personalized attention through adaptive computer programs often called content providers. The teachers role in a blended learning model (I should say the blended learning model I worked in as there are many breeds of blended learning and not all of them work like this) is to curate the computer programs that students engage in, track student performance, and intervene with personal instruction when a computer program is unable to teach a specific concept to a specific child. In theory, this should allow one teacher to effectively instruct a large number of students while the students still receive high quality personal attention exactly when they need it. Teaching for two years on the frontiers of blended learning gave me a glimpse of how powerful and world changing data backed web applications can be. It also taught me very how far we are from a day where a computer program might be able to serve as a child’s primary educator. </p>
<p>This gap, between where the latest technology is and where it could be is where I want to work. With every new line of code we can see a little bit farther and build something a little bit better, inching always towards a future that is more fair, more prosperous, and more free.                 </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I started out thinking that I was going to be an art historian. Somewhere in the middle of my undergraduate years I switched to studying ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
